Guide to the Joseph Brewer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Joseph Brewer papers
1922-1979
YCAL MSS 641
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.42
(2 boxes)
The collection contains correspondence, writings, and photographs. Correspondence includes autograph and typescripts letters from Harold Acton, Iris Barry, Charles Fisk, Katherine Anne Porter, John Strachey and others. There is a small amount of outgoing letters among the correspondence. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts and printed versions of writings by Brewer, including "20th Century Typography in the Netherlands." Photographs include ones by Milton Horn and ones of Katherine Anne Porter by George Platt Lynes.
Brewer, Joseph, 1898-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Elysium Press on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Joseph Hillyer Brewer (1898-1991)
Joseph Hillyer Brewer, American publisher, librarian, and president of Olivet College. He was born in 1898 and died in New York City in 1991.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, writings, and photographs. Correspondence includes autograph manuscript and typescripts letters from Harold Acton, Iris Barry, Charles Fisk, Katherine Anne Porter, John Strachey and others. There is a small amount of outgoing letters among the correspondence. Writings include autograph and typescript drafts and printed versions of writings by Brewer, including "20th Century Typography in the Netherlands." Photographs include ones by Milton Horn and ones of Katherine Anne Porter by George Platt Lynes.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence, 1922-1979. II. Other Papers, 1930-1976.
Authors, American -- 20th Century; Printing -- Netherlands; Photographs; Acton, Harold, 1904-1994; Barry, Iris, 1895-1969; Brewer, Joseph, 1898-; Fisk, Charles; Horn, Milton, 1906-1995; Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980; Strachey, John, 1901-1963
- Correspondence, 1922-1979; Series I; 1; (1 box)
  - Acton, Harold, 1944-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood: relating to, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Barry, Iris, 1945-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Berman, Eugene, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Berman, Leonid, 1949-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biala, Janice, 1950-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bianco, Pamela; Hartmann, George, 1946-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Borgese, Elizabeth Mann, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Claflin, Agnes Rindge; Claflin, Philip, 1949-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dana, Richard H., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dole, William, 1958-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fisk, Charles, 1956-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Ford, Gerald, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Galantiere, Lewis, 1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graeffe, Didier and Lotte, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hartley, L. P., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hitchcock, Henry Russell, 1945-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Horn, Milton, 1953-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hughes, Richard, 1973, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hughes-Stanton, Blair R., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hungiville, Maurice re: Ezra Pound, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mann, Golo, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1944-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Quennell, Peter, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ridge, Lola, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Rothenstein, John and Elizabeth, 1948-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Strachey, Anne, 1937-1948 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Strachey, John, 1922-1959 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - Thomson, Virgil, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Van Vechten, James Brown, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - West, Herbert, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Williams-Ellis, Sir Clough; Williams-Ellis, Lady Amabel; and Williams-Ellis, Susan, 1931-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1939-1973 (Box 1, Folder 39-43)
  - Correspondence relating to Ford Maddox Ford, 1954-1966 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Other Papers, 1930-1976; Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Publications by Brewer, 1946-1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Typescript drafts by Brewer, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "20th Century Typography in the Netherlands" by Joseph Brewer, autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Photographs by Milton Horn, undated (Box 2, Folder 48-50)
  - Photographs of Katherine Anne Porter by George Platt Lynes, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)